# Subhadatta Samal

Extensive 6+ years of work experience in web development with **ReactJS**.

203, Shri Balaji Nilaya, Marathahalli, Bangalore-560037. subhadattasamal24@gmail.com 9938167158 linkedin.com/in/subhadatta-samal

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Hexaware Technologies**, Bangalore — *Sr Software Engineer*

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

# **Mahindra First Choice Wheels,** Bangalore — Associate Software Engineer

JULY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2020

## **Health5c Wellness Solution**, Bangalore — *Software Engineer*

MARCH 2017 - JUNE 2018

## **Altair Engineering**, Bangalore — Project Trainee

MARCH 2016 - MARCH 2017

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Indira Gandhi Institute of Technology,** Sarang, Odisha — *MCA*

JULY 2013 - MAY 2016

## **Institute of Mathematics & Application,** Bhubaneswar, Odisha — B.Sc(Mathematics & Computing)

JULY 2009 - MAY 2013

## **Maharishi College of Natural Law**, Bhubaneswar, Odisha — +2 Science

JULY 2007 - MAY 2009

## **Saraswati Vidya Mandir,** Bhubaneswar, Odisha — Matriculation

MAY 2007

#### **SUMMARY**

Extensive 6+ years of work experience in web development with **ReactJS**.

More than a year of experience in cross-platform mobile app development with **React Native**.

Having experience on technologies like PWA, SSR and SEO.

Experience in CICD and SonarQube implementation.

Involved in various projects like Ecommerce, Social Media, Health Care, Vehicle Inspection, Outlet Management System, Digitization etc.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, Redux-thunk, Redux-saga, TypeScript, NextJS.

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Material-UI

NodeJS, ExpressJS.

NPM, Webpack, PM2, NSSM, NGINX

#### **FUN DOING**

Photo Editing using Adobe Photoshop.

Video Editing using Adobe premiere pro.

### **PROJECTS**

**NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT** 

## **Protocol Digitalization** — *ReactJS Developer*

#### TECHNOLOGY USED:

Platform : Windows

Language : ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Python, NET.

IDE : Visual Code Studio.

Module Bundler : Webpack

**DESCRIPTION:** Protocol Digitalization is an initiative with a goal of creating a digitized library for publicly available protocols.

This initiative will improve institutional knowledge and enable digital data flow for consumption into downstream business systems, tools, and workflows.

This application includes functionalities like protocol detail, section extraction, compare protocol versions, Compare protocols across studies, search, follow/unfollow protocol.

It also includes additional functionalities like quality check and admin role.

CLIENT: IQVIA

**COMPANY:** Hexaware

**ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:** 

Requirement analysis and development.

Participates in technical discussions related to new functionality, products and framework.

Developed wireframes and task flows based on business needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly UI.

JANUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

## **AutoInspekt** — *ReactJS Developer*

### **TECHNOLOGY USED**

Platform : Ubuntu 18.04

Language : ReactJS, Redux, Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, PHP.

IDE : Visual Code Studio.

Module Bundler : Webpack

**DESCRIPTION:** A comprehensive, independent, unbiased inspection service to help you determine the quality of a vehicle.

The primary goal of this application is to overcome the issue of installing the application for a single inspection.

Users will be sent with a unique URL for the inspection where the user needs to validate his mobile number to start the inspection.

**CLIENT:** Mahindra First Choice **ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:** 

Requirement analysis and development.

Participates in technical discussions related to new functionality, products and framework.

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly UI.

JANUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

## **AutoInspekt iOS App** — React Native Developer

### TECHNOLOGY USED:

Platform : Ubuntu 18.04 Language : React Native, PHP. IDE : Visual Code Studio.

Module Bundler : Webpack

**DESCRIPTION:** Autoinspekt is a car evaluation package to help

CLIENT: Mahindra First Choice ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:

Requirement analysis and development.

Participates in technical discussions related to new functionality, products and framework.

determine the quality of the car. With Autoinspekt, get the speed of automation and the assurance of physical inspection.

Our qualified engineers take care to thoroughly inspect the vehicle across a comprehensive checklist and provide a detailed evaluation report, including vehicle history and stolen vehicle report.

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly User Interface.

MARCH 2019 - NOVEMBER 2020

## **Outlet Management System**—ReactJS Developer

### TECHNOLOGY USED:

Platform : Ubuntu 18.04

Language : ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, HTML5, CSS3

IDE : Visual Code Studio.

Module Bundler : Webpack

**DESCRIPTION:** OMS is a dealer facing web application where the dealer manages all kinds of information regarding stocks, leads, offers and customer complaints.

Here the dealer can add or edit its stocks which will be displayed on the customer portal and can see its stock leads come from the customer portal. Also dealers can add their private leads when customers come directly to him.

This application has two kinds of users like dealers and area managers. Area managers can check dealer performance and manage dealers. OMS also has a dealer facing Instant Cash Offer portal where dealers will recheck all the information given by the user and generate a final price. If the user agrees to that, then the dealer closes the deal.

AUGUST 2018 - NOVEMBER 2020

### **MFC-Website**—ReactJS Developer

**DESCRIPTION:** Mahindra First Choice is a customer facing application for those who are interested in buying or selling pre-owned cars. If a customer is interested in buying a used car, they can see details and specifications of a list of available used cars in their city. They can also get dealer information by submitting their details.

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

## **Oxygen Global GMCabs** — React Developer

**DESCRIPTION:** This application was for GMCabs drivers who are assigned with an oxygen card for their everyday transaction credit.

This application facilitates functionalities like activate card, balance check, balance transfer, Coupons etc.

CLIENT: Mahindra First Choice ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:

Requirement analysis and development.

Participates in technical discussions related to new functionality, products and framework.

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly User Interface.

**CLIENT**: Mahindra First Choice **ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES**:

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly User Interface.

**CLIENT**: GMCabs

COMPANY: Health5c Wellness

MARCH 2017 - JUNE 2018

## **KeepMeFit** —React Developer

**DESCRIPTION:** KeepMeFit Social Fitness Platform is a free service that allows you to connect with friends, relatives and coworkers with different fitness devices and apps.

One can view his or her friends profile containing its active challenge, communities created, achievements, number of followers and posts. Not only that, he or she can comment, like, share that post.

MARCH 2017 - JUNE 2018

## **MEDSIS** —React Developer

**DESCRIPTION:** MEDSIS is the trusted and familiar home where people will find a healing touch.

It connects them with everything they need to take good care of themselves and their family – assessing health issues, finding the right doctor, booking diagnostic tests, obtaining medicines, storing health records or learning new ways to live healthier.

MARCH 2016 - MARCH 2017

## **PBS Control Center** —React Developer

**DESCRIPTION:** PBSCC is a product for easy configurations for the admins who have to run many complex commands on console for administration of the PBS product.

### **AWARDS**

Won Star Performer Of the Quarter in my current company.

Won many medals as an athlete and was part of cultural activities at College and School.

Won a scholarship in my 5th and 7th standard.

### **STRENGTHS**

Willingness to learn, highly dedicated, assertive and team player.

CLIENT: Health5c Wellness
ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly User Interface.

**CLIENT: MEDSIS** 

COMPANY: Health5c Wellness ROLES and RESPONSIBILITIES:

Developed wireframes and task flows based on user's needs.

Created a very intuitive, user-friendly User Interface.

CLIENT: ALTAIR COMPANY: ALTAIR

#### **PERSONAL DETAIL**

**Date of Birth:** 31<sup>st</sup> July 1991

**Languages:** Odia, Hindi and English

### **Hobbies:**

Playing cricket, Yoga, Playing Badminton, Swimming and Listening to music.